# **Daehwa Kim**

407 South Craig Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 daehwak@andrew.cmu.edu • +1 415 937 4111 • https://daehwa.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is to invent technologies that could change the interaction paradigm as if the invention of "mouse" paved the way for the world of GUIs. I believe that preferable devices by users could decide next decades of interaction paradigm. To do so, I care about the tangled relationship between what humans are already familiar with, feel comfortable with, and emotionally attracted to, and what kind of technological / design problems to solve. Some demonstrations of this idea are published - explored novel sensing principles of segmenting effortless finger touch (AtaTouch) and shifting the form factor of the micro-gesture sensing device to a wristband from a ring (EtherPose). I presented papers at ACM CHI and UIST and have received two Honorable Mention awards at CHI.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Ph.D. student, Carnegie Mellon University, School of Computer Science,

Sep 2022 – Current

**Human-Computer Interaction Institute** 

Advised by Prof. Chris Harrison at Future Interfaces Group

## M.Sc., KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- Advised by Prof. Geehyuk Lee at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
- Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)

### B.S., UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- Computer Science and Engineering (Major) and Electrical Engineering (Minor)
- Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, University of the Arts London, London, UK

Jul 2018

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Meta Reality Labs, Redmond, WA

- Research Intern
- Mentor: Dr. Eric Whitmire

### Future Interfaces Group, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022

May 2023 – Aug 2023

- Research Associate, Human-Computer Interaction Institute
- Advisor: Prof. Chris Harrison

#### KAIST HCI Lab, Daejeon

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

- Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing
- Advisor: Prof. Geehyuk Lee

### Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

Jan 2018 – Mar 2018

Research Intern

# AWARDS & HONORS

## Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2022

May 2022

 Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022.

#### Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021

May 2021

<u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan.

## Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

Feb 2021

■ Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"

### Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

Tuition + academic funding every semester for the top rank in entrance exam

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] Hui-Shyong Yeo, Erwin Wu, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Juyoung Lee, Hyung-il Kim, Seo Young Oh, Luna Takagi, Woontack Woo, Hideki Koike, and Aaron J Quigley, "OmniSense: Exploring Novel Input Sensing and Interaction Techniques on Mobile Device with Omni-Directional Camera" in *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Hamburg, Germany, Apr 2023.
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, and Chris Harrison, "EtherPose: Continuous Hand Pose Tracking with Wrist-Worn Antenna Impedance" in *Proceedings of the 35th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Bend, Oregon, USA, Oct 2022.
- [3] Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022. Best Paper Honorable Mention Award; Top 5%
- [4] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. <u>Best Paper Honorable Mention Award</u>; Top 5%
- [5] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of* the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020.
- [6] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings* of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020.

## ACADEMIC SERVICE

#### Reviewer

• SIGGRAPH Asia '23 Poster, UIST '23, CHI '23, UIST '22, CHI '22 LBW, IMWUT '21, CHI '21 LBW